Guide to the Loy Connell Smith and Eunice Andrews Smith Bland Papers, 1958-1999 RL.10009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Loy Connell Smith and Eunice Andrews Smith Bland papers
1958-1999
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bland, Eunice Andrews Smith, 1928-
RL.10009
2.5 Linear Feet
Dr. Loy Connell Smith (1925-1968) and his wife, Eunice Andrews Smith (b. 1928), were Southern Baptist missionaries to Nigeria from 1959 through 1968. Collection includes family correspondence, photographs, hospital publications, and audiovisual material from the Smith family's time as missionaries in Nigeria. Contains information about the death of Dr. Loy Connell Smith in a car accident and the Smith family's subsequent return to the United States.
1875 Items
Access Restrictions
RESTRICTED: Box 2 is closed to researchers until 2022. Box 3 contains original audiovisual materials.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Loy Connell Smith and Eunice Andrews Smith Bland Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2012.
Biographical and Historical Note
Loy Connell Smith (b. 1925) and Eunice Andrews Smith (b. 1928) were originally from North Carolina and married in 1949. They were appointed as missionaries to Nigeria by the Southern Baptist Foreign Missions Board in 1958, and after a year of seminary, moved to Ogbomosho, Nigeria, where they worked in medicine. Dr. L.C. Smith worked as a staff physician at the Baptist Hospital, while Eunice Smith taught nursing and worked in the mission's medical laboratory. The couple had three children.
On May 16, 1968, a car accident in Nigeria killed Dr. L.C. Smith and severely injured Eunice. The family buried him in Ogbomosho. In August, Eunice and the children returned to the United States where she worked at the Foreign Mission Board's Africa Office. She married Dr. Thomas A. Bland in 1979. Dr. Bland died in 2010.
Collection Overview
Collection includes family correspondence, photographs, audiovisual tapes and reels, and materials collected by the Smiths regarding their work at the Baptist Hospital. Correspondence has been sorted chronologically by year. Letters between Eunice Andrews Smith and her mother, Annie Wells Andrews, are restricted for 10 years (until 2022). More information about the history of the family can be found in the biographical and background files in Box 1.
The collection also contains a significant amount of information surrounding the Smiths' car accident and Dr. L.C. Smith's death in 1968. Materials on this event include correspondence, records and films of his funeral and memorial services, and materials about memorial funds and plaques in honor of Dr. Smith's service.
Related Material
This collection is part of a larger group of Southern Baptist Missionaries in Nigeria. Related collections include the Pool Family Papers, the McGee Family Papers, and the Roberson Family Papers.
Nigeria -- History -- 20th century; Married people in missionary work -- Africa; Missions -- Africa; Missions -- Nigeria -- History; Audiovisual materials; Baptists -- Missions -- Nigeria; Bland, Eunice Andrews Smith, 1928-; Smith, Loy Connell, 1925-1968; Bland, Eunice Andrews Smith, 1928-; Southern Baptist Convention. Foreign Mission Board
- Smith Family Materials, 3 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Box 2 of this collection is closed to research until 2022. Box 3 is restricted because it contains audiovisual materials; these are closed until use copies can be made.
  - Collection Outline and Information (Box 1)
  - Loy Connell Smith and Eunice Andrews Smith timelines and narratives (Box 1)
  - Appointment as Foreign Missionaries, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Holiday letters to family and friends, 1959-1972 (Box 1)
  - Connell's letters to family, 1959-1966 (Box 1)
  - General correspondence, 1959-1967, 9 folders (Box 1)
  - General correspondence, 1968 (before accident) (Box 1)
  - General correspondence, 1968 (after accident) (Box 1)
  - Death of Loy Connell Smith, 1968-1969, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Ogbomosho Baptist Hospital materials, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
  - Return to the United States, 1968 (Box 1)
  - L.C. Smith Memorial Fund, Nigerian Baptist Convention, 1969-1975 (Box 1)
  - L.C. Smith Memorial Fund, Foreign Mission Board, 1968-1975 (Box 1)
  - Death of Dr. Emanuel Dahunsi, 20 Jan. 1979 (Box 1)
  - L.C. Smith medical certificates (photocopies), 1948-1962 (Box 1)
  - Plaque for L.C. Smith at Ogbomosho Baptist Hospital, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Plaque for L.C. Smith at Bowman Gray School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, N.C., 1971 (Box 1)
  - L.C. Smith Memorial Chapel, Chalybeate Springs Baptist Church, N.C., 1969 (Box 1)
  - Eunice's trip to Nigeria, 5th anniversary memorial service, 1973 (Box 1)
  - 50th Anniversary of Ogbomosho Hospital, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Melba Smith's trip to Nigeria, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Death of Loy Connell Smith Jr., 1995 (Box 1)
  - Loy Connell Smith, Jr. Memorial Fund, Baptist Medical Center, Nigeria, 1995-1999 (Box 1)
  - L.C. Smith's publications in medical journals, 1955-1964 and undated (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1960 and 1963 (Box 1)
  - Family photographs, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Letters from Eunice Andrews Smith to her mother, Annie Wells Andrews, 1959-1968, 4 folders (Box 2)
    CLOSED: This material is closed to research until 2022.
  - Audiovisual Materials, early 1960s to 1975 and undated; 1; 0.5 Linear Feet
    Access Restrictions
    Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.
    - Tape letter from Mrs. L.C. Smith to Mrs. D.B. Andrews, early 1960s; 13
      - Original 1/4-inch open reel, early 1960s (Box 1, Audio-reel RL10009-RR-0009)
    - Tape letter from L.C. Smith to Mrs. D.B. Andrews, Nigerian music, drumming and singing, early 1960s; 12
      - Original 1/4-inch open reel, early 1960s (Box 1, Audio-reel RL10009-RR-0008)
    - Tape letter to Rev. T.S. Smith, early 1960s; 11
      - Original 1/4-inch open reel, early 1960s (Box 1, Audio-reel RL10009-RR-0007)
    - Tape letter from Mrs. L.C. Smith to Mr. Truman Smith, Christmas tape I, early 1960s; 8
      - Original 1/4-inch open reel, early 1960s (Box 1, Audio-reel RL10009-RR-0001)
    - Tape letter to Mr. Truman Smith, early 1960s; 9
      - Original 1/4-inch open reel, early 1960s (Box 1, Audio-reel RL10009-RR-0004)
    - Tape letter from Mrs. L.C. Smith to Mr. Truman Smith, Christmas tape II, early 1960s; 10
      - Original 1/4-inch open reel, early 1960s (Box 1, Audio-reel RL10009-RR-0005)
    - Tape letter from L.C. Smith to Mrs. Truman Smith, November 17, 1961, 1961 November 17; 1
      - Original 1/4-inch open reel, 1961 November 17 (Box 1, Audio-reel RL10009-RR-0003)
    - Tape letter from Dr. L.C. Smith to Mr. Truman Smith, August 8, 1963, 1963 August 8; 2
      - Original 1/4-inch open reel, 1963 August 8 (Box 1, Audio-reel RL10009-RR-0006)
    - Tape letter from Dr. L.C. Smith to Mrs. Truman Smith, October 1963, 1963 October; 3
      - Original 1/4-inch open reel, 1963 October (Box 1, Audio-reel RL10009-RR-0002)
    - Funeral and burial taken by TV station for loca news, 1968 May 23; 4
      - Original 16mm, si., b&w, 1968 May 23 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10009-16mm-0001)
    - Memorial service, Ogbomosho, May 28, 1978; widow, Eunice Smith present, 1973 May 28; 5
      - Original audiocassette, 1973 May 28 (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL10009-CS-0001)
    - Memorial service, Ogbomosho, daugher present, unveiling of head stones of Dr. L.C. Smith and Miss Alice Miller, 1975 May 28; 6
      - Original 1/4-inch open reel, 1975 May 28 (Box 1, Audio-reel RL10009-RR-0014)
    - Smith memorial service, undated; 14
      - Original audiocassette, undated (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL10009-CS-0002)
    - Final service (with commentary) in memory of Dr. Loy Connell Smith of the Baptist Mission of Nigeria, undated; 18
      - Original 1/4-inch open reel, undated (Box 1, Audio-reel RL10009-RR-0013)
    - untitled, circa 1961; 7
      - Original 8mm, circa 1961 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10009-8mm-0001)
    - untitled, undated; 15
      - Original 1/4-inch open reel, undated (Box 1, Audio-reel RL10009-RR-0010)
    - untitled, undated; 16
      - Original 1/4-inch open reel, undated (Box 1, Audio-reel RL10009-RR-0011)
    - untitled, undated; 17
      - Original 1/4-inch open reel, undated (Box 1, Audio-reel RL10009-RR-0012)